Jinyoung Kim

Data Scientist

Cell: 650-995-2355 jykim.github.io lifidea@gmail.com

Jinyoung (Jin) Kim is a data scientist, data enthusiast and data evangelist. In Snap Inc., he has led various projects on online (A/B) and offline (label-based) metric development, causal inference in the space of social media search and recommendation. In Microsoft, he has tackled challenging modeling and measurement problems in the area of web (Bing), email (Outlook), conversational (Cortana) search.

He has published more than a dozen papers in the area of information retrieval and data mining, and recently published a book titled 'Hello, Data Science", which became a national bestseller (#1 in technology category) in Korea with critical acclaim.

He has taught tutorials in evaluation and measurement of online services in both Microsoft and SIGIR, and consulted various teams in Microsoft on metric and experiment design. He has also served in program committees and organized workshops in SIGIR, WSDM, WWW, ECIR conferences.

Experience

Snap Inc. / Lead Data Scientist

Feb 2017-Present

Technical lead in data science for various evaluation and measurement problems around Snapchat's search and recommendation feature. Main projects include 1) evaluating algorithmically generated stories offline 2) developing a set of AB metrics which predict the user retention, 3) applying causal inference techniques (matching and Diff-in-Diff) for measurement problems in which AB testing is not suitable, such as opt-in notification

Microsoft Web Search and Al Science / Senior Applied Scientist

Aug 2012-Jan 2017

Research scientist on measurement techniques for evaluating the search quality of Bing and other search products. Specialize in improving the quality of editorial judgments, designing offline metrics and experiments. Also wrote 6 research papers in top conferences about these topics. Taught a new employee bootcamp course on human judgment collection / offline evaluation.

Microsoft Research / Research Intern

Jun 2011 - Aug 2011

Developed a user profiling method based on the combination of reading level and topic. Explored applications of the method for personalized search and expert content classification.

T&C Technology / Software Engineer

Jan 2003 - Jan 2006

Designed and developed a billing system for large telephone companies in Korea which can handle millions of transactions a day.

Education

University of Massachusetts at Amherst / Ph.D. in Computer Science

2007 - 2012

Ph.D Dissertation: Retrieval and evaluation techniques for personal information

Seoul National University / B.S. in Electrical Engineering

1999-2007

Graduated with Cum Laude

Selected Publications

(full list here)

Understanding and Modeling Success in Email Search

Jin Young Kim, Nick Craswell, Susan Dumais, Filip Radlinski, Fang Liu. 2017. In Proceedings of the 40th Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR).

Hello, Data Science

Jinyoung Kim, Published by Hanbit Media, 2016.

Explicit In Situ User Feedback for Web Search Results

Jin Young Kim, Jaime Teevan and Nick Craswell. 2016. In Proceedings of the 39th Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR).

Toward Predicting the Outcome of an A/B Experiment for Search Relevance

Lihong Li, Jin Young Kim, and Imed Zitouni. 2015. In Proceedings of the Eighth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM).

Contextual and dimensional relevance judgments for reusable SERP-level evaluation

Peter B. Golbus, Imed Zitouni, Jin Young Kim, Ahmed Hassan, and Fernando Diaz. 2014. In Proceedings of the 23rd international conference on World wide web (WWW).

Understanding Web Search Interactions with Dynamic Results Generated using Implicit Feedback

Jin Young Kim, Mark Cramer, Jaime Teevan, Dmitry Lagun. 2013. In Proceedings of the 22nd ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM).

Relevance Dimensions in Preference-Based IR Evaluation

Jin Young Kim, Gabriella Kazai, Imed Zitouni. 2013. In Proceedings the 35th annual international ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR).

Characterizing web content, user interests, and search behavior by reading level and topic

Jin Young Kim, Kevyn Collins-Thompson, Paul N. Bennett, Susan T. Dumais. 2012. In Proceedings of 5th ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining, Seattle, WA, USA (WSDM).

A Field Relevance Model for Structured Document Retrieval

Jin Young Kim and W. Bruce Croft. 2012. In Proceedings of the 34th European Conference on Information Retrieval (ECIR), Barcelona, Spain.

Patents

Improving Judgment Quality in Side-by-side Evaluation

8/28/2015

Task-level Search Engine Evaluation

8/11/2015

Offline Evaluation of Ranking Functions

11/21/2014

Behavior-based Evaluation of Crowd Worker Quality

6/5/2014

Invited Talks / Tutorial

IR Evaluation: Designing an End-to-End Offline Evaluation Pipeline

Half-day Tutorial in SIGIR'15, Aug 8, 2015.

Data Science in Industry

Department of Mathematics, University of Washington, Jun 4, 2015.